<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Merge Stories</title><link href="http://mergestories.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://mergestories.com/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://mergestories.com/</id><updated>2014-06-10T18:05:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>My first FOSS contribution to Iron Blogger</title><link href="http://mergestories.com/first-FOSS-contribution-to-iron-blogger.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-10T18:05:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Shauna Gordon-McKeon</name></author><id>tag:mergestories.com,2014-06-10:first-FOSS-contribution-to-iron-blogger.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started off as a user of &lt;a href="http://mako.cc/copyrighteous/iron-blogger"&gt;Iron Blogger&lt;/a&gt;, which is both a piece of software and a social group.  Individuals agree to write a blog post every week or pay $5; when enough money is collected, the group meets for pizza and beer.  The Iron Blogger software, which is built off of the &lt;a href="http://www.planetplanet.org/"&gt;Planet feed aggregator&lt;/a&gt;, provides a feed of all the blog posts written by participants combined.  I enjoyed reading this feed but was annoyed that it only showed the most recent 15 posts.  I decided to change Iron Blogger to show more.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was new to FOSS at the time and didn't really know where to begin.  Luckily I was friends with the maintainer of the project and he was able to point me to where the source code was stored (it has since moved).  After several hours of poking around the repository, looking through Planet's documentation, and emailing both my friend and the Planet mailing list, I was able to identify the variable to change.  I'm afraid I don't remember the details of the obstacles I faced, as this was several years ago now.  I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; remember telling my friend, "Okay, I found the variable!  You just need to go to line 37 in the configuration file and change itemsperpage from 15 to, say, 50..."  He told me to submit a patch.  He explained what a patch was and gave me a link to a tutorial that looked something like &lt;a href="http://jungels.net/articles/diff-patch-ten-minutes.html"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.  I was then able to generate a patch, which he merged into the project.  A few years later, the project was put on Github, so you can see the commit (linked below).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a great first contribution to make, because it was something I cared about but also something very straightforward to fix with my programming background (which is not very extensive, but did cover variables and configuration files).  I was also lucky to have someone willing to walk me through the basics of downloading repositories and creating patches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevant Links:
&lt;a href="https://github.com/paultag/iron-blogger/commit/abe5a57a68ccfd4426f1a73bf6d365c7f19e9173"&gt;Patch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="first contribution"></category><category term="project - iron blogger"></category><category term="helped by - friend"></category><category term="helped by -mailing list"></category><category term="helped by - documentation"></category><category term="kind of contribution - code"></category><category term="difficulties encountered - unfamiliar with FOSS"></category><category term="featured"></category></entry><entry><title>Filing a small bug with GIMP</title><link href="http://mergestories.com/small-bug-in-gimp.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-10T18:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Shauna Gordon-McKeon</name></author><id>tag:mergestories.com,2014-06-10:small-bug-in-gimp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been using GIMP for years, but I've never contributed to it.  Recently, some GIMP contributors contacted me about arranging an online event to help them improve their documentation.  I wanted to see how their documentation currently looked, so I went to &lt;a href="http://www.gimp.org/"&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; and started clicking and reading links.  When I got to the link for their &lt;a href="https://git.gnome.org/browse/gimp/plain/INSTALL"&gt;installation guide&lt;/a&gt;, it sent me to a blank page.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to confirm that it wasn't just a problem with my browser, so I opened up the page in both Firefox and Chrome.  Then I asked some friends (the kinds folks on the #openhatch IRC channel) what they saw at the link, and they also saw nothing.  Before I could proceed with the next step, one of them dug up the &lt;a href="https://git.gnome.org/browse/gimp/plain/INSTALL.in"&gt;correct link&lt;/a&gt; for me!  I decided to file a bug so that someone else could make this presumably easy fix.    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To file the bug, I found the project's bug tracker, and within that, the tracker for the GIMP website.  I checked the list of bugs to see if anyone had already reported this problem.  They hadn't, so I wrote up a quick report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevant Links:
&lt;a href="https://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=731472"&gt;bug report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="project - gimp"></category><category term="kind of contribution - bug report"></category><category term="helped by - IRC"></category></entry><entry><title>Reviving debexpo</title><link href="http://mergestories.com/reviving-debexpo.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-30T00:13:57-04:00</updated><author><name>Asheesh Laroia</name></author><id>tag:mergestories.com,2014-05-30:reviving-debexpo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I discovered, through reading the Debian wiki, that there was a new web app created for Debian called Debexpo, and it was nearly ready to replace our existing package review tool, but not quite ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took it upon myself to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email the original authors of the code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to prospective users on IRC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work on it a lot at the yearly Debian conference in 2011 -- I already planned on going, and instead of just socializing, I used the Debconf hack lab space to work on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transition it to a different community that now maintains it -- I did this by intentionally making contribution really easy, and then repeatedly asking for help on the debian-mentors email list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I had a fun time. It is always a pleasure to help Debian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot about the Pylons web framework as a result, which I mostly learned through massive Googling.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevant links:
&lt;a href="http://mentors.debian.net/"&gt;Project website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="project - debian"></category><category term="difficulties encountered - build"></category><category term="helped by - IRC"></category><category term="helped by - web search"></category><category term="kind of contribution - code"></category><category term="kind of contribution - community mangement"></category><category term="featured"></category></entry></feed>