<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Merge Stories</title><link>http://mergestories.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://mergestories.com/feeds/carol-willing.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 12:21:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>A little blue tape goes a long way</title><link>http://mergestories.com/s/a-little-blue-tape-goes-a-long-way/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One year ago, I received an invitation to AdaCamp San Francisco. In the spirit of open source, I volunteered to help with the room set up and AV preparation on the first morning of the event. I arrived early and received my tools -- a tape measure, a room map, and several rolls of blue painters’ tape. I found another AdaCamper who was willing to help me crawl around on the floor and create a blue painters’ tape path throughout the meeting rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? On that day, my contribution was creating an accessible path for others to use and a reminder to all to be respectful of open spaces. Pretty cool to make a contribution that didn’t involve lines of code, git, or code reviews. Even cooler to me, the contribution is something that I have been able to share with other groups in my local community. Sharing open knowledge and skills is one of the cornerstones of open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever wonder if your little contribution to a project or event matters, I believe it does. The beauty of many little contributions, or even one, is that it makes things a little better for others even if only for a moment. The little roll of blue tape might have another use -- it comes in handy for sticking together many small contributions of goodness. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Carol Willing</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 12:21:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:mergestories.com,2014-09-13:s/a-little-blue-tape-goes-a-long-way/</guid><category>project - adacamp</category><category>helped by - community members</category><category>setting - conference</category><category>kind of contribution - misc</category></item></channel></rss>