<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Merge Stories</title><link href="http://mergestories.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://mergestories.com/feeds/heidi-ellis.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://mergestories.com/</id><updated>2014-09-13T12:14:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Helping others contribute to Sahana</title><link href="http://mergestories.com/s/helping-others-contribute-to-sahana/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-13T12:14:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Heidi Ellis</name></author><id>tag:mergestories.com,2014-09-13:s/helping-others-contribute-to-sahana/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm a professor who has students join a humanitarian open source community and make contributions as part of a class. I first became involved in HFOSS (humanitarian free and open source software) in January of 2006.  At that time, Trishan de Lanerolle (now a project manager at IBM) came back from Sri Lanka after spending Christmas break there. He and a group of people were working on &lt;a href="http://eden.sahanafoundation.org/"&gt;the Sahana disaster management system&lt;/a&gt; to try to help victims of disasters, especiallly victims of the Asian tsunami of 2005.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trishan urged me to get involved with the project, and more importantly, to get students involved with the project. During the spring 2006 semester, Ralph Morellis, Trishan and I got two independent study students to download and install the project. We also asked students to make small changes and compile and run the project. We wanted to see if students could work with it.  It turned out that Sahana was easy to install and relatively easy to modify. I have found this a good first step to determine if a project is one that students can participate in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next step was to see if we could actually make a contribution to the project. During summer 2006, we had three interns, two paid and an unpaid volunteer from Bard college, work to develop a Volunteer Management module for Sahana. This module was intended to help register the volunteers for a disaster so that volunteers could be allocated to the proper locations. For instance, to send someone with construction background to help shore up dams. The module was selected because at the time the registration was very rudimentary.  They wanted something that kept track of more than just names and would handle things like occupation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One difficulty that students faced was that during the course of development, the database had to be changed to accommodate the new information. This took some going back and forth with the Sahana team to get a design that was acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the summer, they had developed a Volunteer Management module that was so impressive, the Sahana Foundation flew one student across the country to demo it during the &lt;a href="(http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strong_Angel)"&gt;Strong Angel&lt;/a&gt; III disaster and pandemic simulation held in San Francisco. Strong Angel III brought together technology companies, medical and military personnel, and humanitarian organizations to simulate a response to a disaster and pandemic in order to see how to improve such a response. The Volunteer Management module was used to register the participants of Strong Angel III. I have pictures of the student speaking with the Worldwide Manager of the IBM Crisis Team and working with a Microsoft Soluion Architect, also one of the designers of SSE. We had only been working with Sahana for 7-8 months and I was blown away by what students had accomplished and also by the potential offered by open source involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the lessons that I learned from that experience (which have been reinforced by involvement with a range of projects) are:
&lt;em&gt; Students can make meaningful contributions to open source projects
&lt;/em&gt; The potential to learn is vast and goes far beyond classroom learning
&lt;em&gt; Working with open source gives students experience in developing within a professional environment, learning professional conduct
&lt;/em&gt; Open source allows students to understand the intricacies of working with a large, complex application. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="project - sahana"></category><category term="helped by - community members"></category><category term="helped by - maintainer"></category><category term="kind of contribution - community management"></category></entry></feed>